Senior Finance & Analytics Manager

15 years of leadership driving analytics, insights, and business partnerships

Extensive experience in financial and risk management in global, corporate and local market settings. Expert in financial and regulatory processes including reporting automation and financial system implementation. Leader, mentor, and career developer of cross-functional teams. Advisor to senior leaders, clients, and partners who builds consensus on change and sustainable growth. Process Owner who reduces costs and increases efficiency / ROI. Specialist in Microsoft Office, Advanced Excel, Hyperion, Oracle Essbase, Cognos/TM1, Netsuite, Adaptive, Power Bl/Tableau, Quickbooks, Bloomberg, Coupa Procurement, SharePoint, Workday, and Peoplesoft HR, Clarity, SAP/Concur. Fluent in English, French, and Russian. Recently completed Certificate Program from Columbia Fu School of Engineering in Data Science, Python, Pandas, Matplotlib, Flask, Machine Learning, SQL, RESTFUL API, JSON/XML, VBA, R, HTML, CSS, Javascript, d3, Big Data and Others.

Technical Skills:

- Strategic Planning & Execution
- **Financial Process Automation**
- Project Strategy & Delivery
- Treasury Functions & P&L's
- **Budgeting & Forecasting**
- **Business Decision Support**
- Investment Optimization/CBA's •
- Financial Modeling & Analytics •
- Team Leader & Collaborator
- FX, IR, Operational Risk Mgmt.
 Executive/Board of Directors Reporting
 - Financial System Implementation
 - Regulatory & Compliance (SOX, CCAR)
 - Managerial & Financial/Legal Allocations
 - Big Data Quality, Analytics & Visualization

Professional Experience

RED LUXURY GROUP 2017 - 2020

Sales, Marketing and Client Services Associate - New York, NY

Delivered monthly target sales for global French luxury brand through personalized service to high-end clients.

- Delivered "best in class" client servicing through customized product knowledge, ensuring customer satisfaction through timely fulfillment of in-store, telephone, and online sales to predominantly French-only-speaking clients.
- Managed daily, weekly and monthly financial reporting, ensured accurate cash/credit receipts and deposits.
- Elevated brand recognition through marketing campaigns and promotions.

AMERICAN EXPRESS 2005 - 2017

HQ Finance Manager - Global Operations and Technology (GBT) - Paris, France/New York, NY (2011 - 2017) Automated planning, forecasting, and results analysis for \$300M+ Pan-European and Global Operations Overheads as subset of \$700M Global Operations budget. Served as main point-of-contact for GBT investment and reengineering projects.

- Ensured Operational controls and productivity by setting and tracking KPI's across 18 EMEA Markets. Lead team of 4 Finance Analysts in regional planning, forecasting, analysis, regulatory, and segment reporting.
- Partnered across 15 multinational business segments to deliver and report multi-year 6% YOY cost reductions including Pan-EMEA charge-outs across 18 markets through improved forecasting and results analysis accuracy.
- Delivered 12% ROI target through controlled tracking of \$80M Operations & Technology investment spending.
- Supported financial system migration to ERP cloud-based Netsuite in 40 markets as Finance Project Manager.

HQ Finance Manager - Global Commercial Card (GCC) - New York, NY (2009 - 2011)

Lead all centralized planning, forecasting, results analysis and decision support activities for Global Corporate Payments.

- Coordinated production & presentation of monthly results reports for Global Business SVP & Leadership Team.
- Improved forecasting accuracy by streamlining centralized planning framework, models, processes, repositories.
- Developed automated, rolling forecast models to predict Global Commercial Card charge volume, revenues, expenses and net income. Reported financial results to senior leadership within only three days of financial close.
- Operationalized client level charge volume forecasting and reporting, capturing volumes at global, regional, market, segment (GBP, LM, MM, SME,) BAU, new and carry-over win, new and carry-over loss, levels.

Stacy J. Giauque • Page 2

HQ Treasury Manager - Global Treasury (TRS) - New York, NY (2008 - 2009)

Sized sources and uses of funding in Global AXP, US, and foreign markets. Identified opportunities to reduce funding costs.

- Improved enterprise hedging strategy by assessing strategic benefits of existing/alternative hedging instruments.
- Sized origin, uses, carry cost, and rate & term laddering of \$26B capital funding during global financial crisis.
- Reduced FX volatility by +/- \$50M for 16 of the highest exposed currencies using options/forwards as a hedge.
- Managed reporting of company-wide liquidity run-off to senior leadership and regulators in 2008 liquidity crisis.

HQ Finance Manager - EMEA Global Business Travel (GBT) - London, UK (2007 - 2008)

Fostered expansion of revenue streams through quarterly forecasting of P&L's and monthly profitability analysis.

- Improved GBT profitability by \$3M for 300+ customers in 18 markets with margin analytics and P&L reporting.
- Drove \$20M in Consulting business revenues through new prospects and initiatives reporting across 18 markets.

US Finance Manager - Capabilities, Lending & Acquisition (CCSG) - New York, NY (2006 - 2007)

Drove analytical and strategic best practices for investment optimization decisions. Supported Card Capability, Product Development, Acquisition and Cross-sell teams across US Consumer Card Business, largest business segment at AXP.

- Optimized investment spending using end-to-end analytics of first-ever online target-marketing application.
- Managed forecasting and reporting of \$95M budget for Strategic Marketing Capabilities and Direct Mail Services.

Finance & Controllership Intern (GCS) - Phoenix, AZ & Paris, France (2005)

Spearheaded controllership and compliance audit for GCS/GBT French market ranked second in sales behind the U.S.

• Ensured US and French compliance with SOX, FASB regulations for \$1.5B in revenues across 29 global markets through comprehensive financial processes audit with special focus on US & local French GAAP requirements.

J.P. MORGAN CHASE 2003 – 2004

Fixed Income & FX Sales & Research Associate (Treasury Services) – Brussels, Belgium (2004)

Developed and maintained superior client satisfaction for users of treasury services products. Served as advisor to support treasury decisions, resolve issues, assess progress, and align products with client objectives.

- Conducted extensive market analysis resulting in new relationships with six Luxembourg I-banks (€14B+ in assets) gaining €330M in projected sales.
- Provided ad-hoc empirical and financial analysis for FX and Fixed Income trades, including CDS, CDO, ABS. **Business Account Manager (Global Commercial Card)** Salt Lake City, UT (2003)

Coordinated RFP process, due diligence, product development, and marketing to land corporate card co-branding deals at three international partner banks.

- Garnered GCC Small & Medium Business Account Manager Service Recognition Awards three times straight.
- Marketed and developed internationally-issued corporate credit card products as member of international product development team (\$2M of brand equity.)

Education & Training

Certificate, Data Analytics & Visualization Bootcamp, Columbia University **International Certificate in Corporate Finance (ICCF),** Columbia University

Masters of Business Administration (MBA) in Finance & Global Management, Brigham Young University – Provo, UT Foreign Language Area Studies, Full Tuition, Stipend Scholar, Dow Chemical Waste-To-Energy Consultant

Bachelor of Science (BS) in Economics & Bachelor of Arts (BA) in French, Northern Arizona University – Flagstaff, AZ *Full Tuition Scholar, French Theatre Club, Shrine of Ages Chorale, University Women's Soccer*

Russian Language & Business Research Program, Brigham Young University – St. Petersburg, Russia
International Economics & French Language Study Abroad, Université Paul Valérey – Montpellier, France
French Language & Business Research Program, Brigham Young University – Dakar, Senegal
Asia Business Research Program, Brigham Young University – China, Japan, Singapore, Vietnam